Mss.Rec.254 Mss.Rec.254
American Philosophical Society
Fieldwork in the Menominee language
1999-2000
Mss.Rec.254
American Philosophical Society
11.0 Tape(s)
11 sound cassettes (10 hr., 11 min.): analog, 1 7/8 ips, stereo.
Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.
Arrangement note
Original tapes numbered 4-5, 9-13, 15-18.
Conditions Governing Access
This material has access restrictions. Please consult a curator for details.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Presented by Rebecca Kavanaugh. This material was recorded with the assistance of a Phillips Fund grant.
Menominee Indians--Folklore; Menominee Indians--Social life and customs; Menominee language; Sound recordings
- Audio recordings
  - Introductions and conversation, 1999-07-13; 04-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:26; Floring, Marie; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Nelson, Lillian; Skubitz, Sarah; Zhuckkahosee, Tillie
    Existence and Location of Originals note
    This file is a compressed, digitized version of the original. The APS Library maintains the original format (Audiocassette) as well as an uncompressed digitized version of this recording.
    Keshena (Wis.); Menominee language
  - Story about two brothers, 1999-07-13; 04-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:56; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Nelson, Lillian
    Brothers--Folklore; Keshena (Wis.); Menominee Indians--Folklore; Menominee language
  - Story about two dogs and a skunk, 1999-07-13; 04-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:23; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Nelson, Lillian
    Dogs--Folklore; Keshena (Wis.); Menominee Indians--Folklore; Menominee language; Skunks--Folklore
  - Words and phrases used around the house, 1999-07-13; 04-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:59; Floring, Marie; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Nelson, Lillian; Skubitz, Sarah; Zhuckkahosee, Tillie
  - Self-introduction, 1999-07-13; 04-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:17; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.
    Scope and Contents note
    Speaker not identified on recording or accompanying documentation.
    Keshena (Wis.); Menominee Indians; Menominee language
  - Self-introduction and prayer, 1999-07-13; 04-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:22; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.
    Keshena (Wis.); Menominee Indians--Religion; Menominee language; Prayers
  - Self-introduction and the Bullfrog Song, 1999-07-13; 04-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:17; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.
    Words to song given in Menominee, then English. Speaker not identified on recording or accompanying documentation.
    Keshena (Wis.); Menominee Indians--Music; Menominee language
  - Self-introduction, Angela Loudbear, 1999-07-13; 04-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:14; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Loudbear, Angela
    Primarily in Menominee.
  - Story of the Partridge Dance, 1999-07-13; 04-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:05; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Loudbear, Angela
    Story told in Menominee, then in English.
    Keshena (Wis.); Menominee Indians--Folklore; Menominee language
  - Acknowledgement of mentors, 1999-07-13; 04-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:05; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.
    Speakers not identified on recording or accompanying documentation.
  - Discussion of goals for recording session, 1999-08-02; 04-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:59; Floring, Marie; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Nelson, Lillian; Skubitz, Sarah; Zhuckkahosee, Tillie
  - Story about learning and teaching Menominee, 1999-08-02; 04-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:38; Floring, Marie; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.
    In Menominee only.
    Keshena (Wis.); Menominee Indians; Menominee language--Study and teaching
  - Story about learning and teaching Menominee, 1999-08-02; 04-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:04; Floring, Marie; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.
    In English.
  - Self-introduction, Angela Loudbear, 1999-08-02; 04-14; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:00; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Loudbear, Angela
    Given in Menominee, then in English.
  - Story of the Partridge Dance, 1999-08-02; 04-15; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:16; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Loudbear, Angela
  - Story of the Partridge Dance, 1999-08-02; 04-16; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:50; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Loudbear, Angela
    Keshena (Wis.); Menominee Indians--Folklore
  - Prayer, 1999-08-02; 04-17; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:43; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.
    Prayer introduced in English and given in Menominee. Speaker not identified on recording or accompanying documentation.
  - Prayer, 1999-08-02; 04-18; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:29; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.
    Keshena (Wis.); Menominee Indians--Religion; Prayers
  - Discussion of Menominee stories just heard, 1999-08-02; 04-19; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:49; Floring, Marie; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Shawano, Lavina; Skubitz, Sarah; Snow, Margaret; Zhuckkahosee, Tillie
    Conversation in English and Menominee.
  - Story from childhood about a forbidden lake and a fireball that came from a spring, 1999-08-02; 04-20; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:04; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Shawano, Lavina
  - Story from childhood about a forbidden lake and a fireball that came from a spring, 1999-08-02; 04-21; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:17; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Shawano, Lavina
    In English only.
  - Story about drownings and the importance of respecting the land, 1999-08-02; 05-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:41; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Shawano, Lavina
  - Discussion of stories just heard, 1999-08-02; 05-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:26; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Shawano, Lavina; Skubitz, Sarah; Zhuckkahosee, Tillie
    Discussion primarily in Menominee.
  - Story about advice from elders to use tobacco in making prayers, 1999-08-02; 05-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:40; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Snow, Margaret; Zhuckkahosee, Tillie
    Two personal accounts given, one in English, one in Menominee, then English.
    Keshena (Wis.); Menominee Indians--Religion; Menominee language; Prayers; Tobacco
  - Story of Indians in the West using tobacco to protect their home from a storm, 1999-08-02; 05-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:46; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Shawano, Lavina; Skubitz, Sarah; Zhuckkahosee, Tillie
    Indians of North America--West (U.S.); Keshena (Wis.); Menominee Indians--Religion; Menominee language; Prayers; Tobacco
  - Stories and discussion of the use of tobacco and cedar poles to protect homes from storms, 1999-08-02; 05-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:07; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Shawano, Lavina
  - Self-introduction, Tillie Zhuckkahosee, 1999-08-02; 05-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:16; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Zhuckkahosee, Tillie
  - Self-introduction, Lavina Shawano, 1999-08-02; 05-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:10; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Shawano, Lavina
  - Self-introduction, Sarah Skubitz, 1999-08-02; 05-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:06; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Skubitz, Sarah
  - Self-introduction, Marie Floring, 1999-08-02; 05-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:29; Floring, Marie; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.
  - Self-introduction, Margaret Snow, 1999-08-02; 05-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:14; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Snow, Margaret
  - Discussion of compensation for recording sessions, 1999-08-02; 05-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:11; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.
  - Poem about a little chipmunk, 1999-08-02; 05-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:20; Floring, Marie; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.
    Chipmunks--Folklore; Keshena (Wis.); Menominee language
  - Story about granddaughter and "This Little Piggy" nursery rhyme, 1999-08-02; 05-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:41; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Snow, Margaret
    Introduced in English, then given in Menominee.
    Keshena (Wis.); Menominee language; Nursery rhymes
  - Story about granddaughter and "This Little Piggy" nursery rhyme, 1999-08-02; 05-14; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:04; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Snow, Margaret
    Keshena (Wis.); Nursery rhymes
  - Translation of "Itsy Bitsy Spider" nursery rhyme, with discussion, 1999-08-02; 05-15; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:21; Floring, Marie; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Loudbear, Angela; Shawano, Lavina; Skubitz, Sarah; Snow, Margaret; Zhuckkahosee, Tillie
  - Discussion of translation of "This Little Piggy", 1999-08-02; 05-16; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:20; Floring, Marie; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Loudbear, Angela; Shawano, Lavina; Skubitz, Sarah; Snow, Margaret; Zhuckkahosee, Tillie
  - Miscellaneous conversations in Menominee and English, 1999-10-12; 09-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:29; Floring, Marie; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Loudbear, Angela; Shawano, Lavina; Skubitz, Sarah; Snow, Margaret; Zhuckkahosee, Tillie
  - Replay of previously recorded word list, with comments, 1999-11-08; 09-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:02; Floring, Marie; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Loudbear, Angela; Nelson, Lillian; Shawano, Lavina; Skubitz, Sarah; Snow, Margaret; Zhuckkahosee, Tillie
    This recording session was also recorded on a separate machine in a different location. See Related Recording.
  - Discussion of food-related Menominee vocabulary words and their correct spelling, 1999-11-08; 09-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:20:38; Floring, Marie; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Loudbear, Angela; Nelson, Lillian; Shawano, Lavina; Skubitz, Sarah; Snow, Margaret; Zhuckkahosee, Tillie
    This program was also recorded on a separate machine in a different location. See Related Recording. This program ends at the 21:23 mark of the corresponding program.
  - Discussion of food-related Menominee vocabulary words and their correct spelling, 1999-11-08; 09-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:15:30; Floring, Marie; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Loudbear, Angela; Nelson, Lillian; Shawano, Lavina; Skubitz, Sarah; Snow, Margaret; Zhuckkahosee, Tillie
    This program was also recorded on a separate machine in a different location in two sections. See Related Recordings. Begins at 21:50 mark of first corresponding program. Interval from 2:19 to 2:38 covers the gap between the two corresponding programs.
  - Paradigms for "eat," with discussion of correct spelling, 1999-11-08; 09-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:15:43; Floring, Marie; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Loudbear, Angela; Nelson, Lillian; Shawano, Lavina; Skubitz, Sarah; Snow, Margaret; Zhuckkahosee, Tillie
    This program was also recorded on a separate machine in a different location. See Related Recording. This program ends at the 15:52 mark of the corresponding recording.
  - Replay of previously recorded word list, with comments (Recorder B), 1999-11-08; 10-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:04; Floring, Marie; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Loudbear, Angela; Nelson, Lillian; Shawano, Lavina; Skubitz, Sarah; Snow, Margaret; Zhuckkahosee, Tillie
  - Discussion of food-related Menominee vocabulary words and their correct spelling (Recorder B), 1999-11-08; 10-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:24:07; Floring, Marie; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Loudbear, Angela; Nelson, Lillian; Shawano, Lavina; Skubitz, Sarah; Snow, Margaret; Zhuckkahosee, Tillie
    This program was also recorded on a separate machine in a different location in two sections. See Related Recordings. Interval from 20:53 to 21:23 covers the gap between the two corresponding programs. This program ends at the 2:19 mark of the second corresponding recording.
  - Discussion of food-related Menominee vocabulary words and their correct spelling (Recorder B), 1999-11-08; 10-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:13:03; Floring, Marie; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Loudbear, Angela; Nelson, Lillian; Shawano, Lavina; Skubitz, Sarah; Snow, Margaret; Zhuckkahosee, Tillie
    This recording session was also recorded on a separate machine in a different location. This program begins 2:37 into corresponding program. See Related Recording.
  - Paradigms for "eat," with discussion of correct spelling (Recorder B), 1999-11-08; 10-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:18:12; Floring, Marie; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Loudbear, Angela; Nelson, Lillian; Shawano, Lavina; Skubitz, Sarah; Snow, Margaret; Zhuckkahosee, Tillie
    This program was also recorded on a separate machine in a different location in two sections. See Related Recordings. The interval from 15:52 to 16:32 covers the gap between the two corresponding programs. This program ends at the 1:35 mark of the second corresponding recording.
  - Paradigms for "eat," with discussion of correct spelling, 1999-11-08; 11-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:16:25; Floring, Marie; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Loudbear, Angela; Nelson, Lillian; Shawano, Lavina; Skubitz, Sarah; Snow, Margaret; Zhuckkahosee, Tillie
    This program was also recorded on a separate machine in a different location in two sections. See Related Recordings. This program begins at the 16:32 mark of the first corresponding program. The interval from 1:35 to 2:01 covers the gap between the two corresponding programs. This program ends at the 14:31 mark of the second corresponding recording.
  - Words and phrases related to schools and education, 1999-12-06; 11-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:14:44; Floring, Marie; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Loudbear, Angela; Nelson, Lillian; Shawano, Lavina; Skubitz, Sarah; Snow, Margaret; Zhuckkahosee, Tillie
    Education; Keshena (Wis.); Menominee language
  - Names of places on the Menominee Reservation, 1999-12-06; 11-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:54; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Loudbear, Angela
    Keshena (Wis.); Menominee Indian Reservation (Wis.); Menominee language; Names, Geographical--Wisconsin
  - Words for relatives, followed by elicitations of verbs, 1999-12-06; 11-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:19:00; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Skubitz, Sarah
    Keshena (Wis.); Menominee Indians--Kinship; Menominee language
  - Paradigms for "eat," with discussion of correct spelling (Recorder B), 1999-11-08; 12-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:15:34; Floring, Marie; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Loudbear, Angela; Nelson, Lillian; Shawano, Lavina; Skubitz, Sarah; Snow, Margaret; Zhuckkahosee, Tillie
    This program was also recorded on a separate machine in a different location. See Related Recordings. This program begins at the 2:01 mark of the corresponding program. The interval from 14:31 to the end is not on the corresponding program.
  - Reading and discussion of Menominee names in Leonard Bloomfield's "Menomini Texts", 2000-03-15; 12-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:38; Floring, Marie; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Skubitz, Sarah; Zhuckkahosee, Tillie
    Bloomfield, Leonard, 1887-1949; Keshena (Wis.); Menominee language; Names, Menominee
  - Reading and discussion of Leonard Bloomfield's commentary in "Menomini Texts", 2000-03-15; 12-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:20; Floring, Marie; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Skubitz, Sarah; Zhuckkahosee, Tillie
    Bloomfield, Leonard, 1887-1949; Keshena (Wis.); Menominee Indians; Menominee language
  - Discussion of stories in Bloomfield's "Texts," past researchers, and Hell-Diver, 2000-03-15; 12-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:19:10; Floring, Marie; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Skubitz, Sarah; Snow, Margaret; Zhuckkahosee, Tillie
    Bloomfield, Leonard, 1887-1949; Horned grebe; Keshena (Wis.); Menominee language; Names, Menominee; Skinner, Alanson, 1886-1925
  - Reading of verb forms from Bloomfield's "Menomini Texts", 2000-03-15; 12-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:15:05; Floring, Marie; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Skubitz, Sarah; Snow, Margaret; Zhuckkahosee, Tillie
  - Elicitation of Menominee sentences, 2000-03-01; 13-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:22:15; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Loudbear, Angela; Skubitz, Sarah
  - Story about a fox, 2000-03-01; 13-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:01; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Skubitz, Sarah
    Foxes--Folklore; Keshena (Wis.); Menominee Indians--Folklore; Menominee language
  - Story of Me'napus roasting ducks, 2000-03-01; 13-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:30; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Skubitz, Sarah
    Keshena (Wis.); Menominee Indians--Folklore; Menominee language; Nanabush (Legendary character)--Legends
  - Story of the white birch, 2000-03-01; 13-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:18; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Skubitz, Sarah
    Birch--Folklore; Keshena (Wis.); Menominee Indians--Folklore; Menominee language
  - Story of a man who could spit beads, 2000-03-01; 13-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:43; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Skubitz, Sarah
  - Discussion why some stories can only be told in the wintertime, 2000-03-01; 13-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:43; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.
    Primary speaker not identified.
  - Discussion of Me'napus, 2000-03-01; 13-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:09; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.
    Keshena (Wis.); Menominee Indians--Folklore; Menominee language; Nanabush (Legendary character)
  - Story of a girl who wanted to go to a dance, 2000-03-01; 13-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:50; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Skubitz, Sarah
    Devil--Folklore; Keshena (Wis.); Menominee Indians--Folklore; Menominee language
  - Story of a woman who didn't teach her child good behavior, 2000-03-01; 13-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:09; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Skubitz, Sarah
    Discipline of children; Keshena (Wis.); Menominee Indians--Folklore; Menominee language
  - Story of Me'napus, 2000-02-23; 15-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:08:05; Floring, Marie; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.
    Menominee Indians--Folklore; Menominee language; Nanabush (Legendary character)--Legends
  - Discussion of stories, John Satterlee, family histories, and miscellaneous topics, 2000-03-15; 15-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:20:32; Floring, Marie; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Skubitz, Sarah; Zhuckkahosee, Tillie
    Keshena (Wis.); Menominee Indians; Menominee Indians--History; Menominee language
  - Group discussion of commonly-used verbs and phrases, 2000-04-03; 15-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:08; Floring, Marie; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Loudbear, Angela; Skubitz, Sarah; Zhuckkahosee, Tillie
    A multi-part, day-long group workshop session to write down commonly-used Menominee verbs, phrases, and other vocabulary for the purposes of creating teaching material. Some of the participants are not identifiable.
    Keshena (Wis.); Menominee language--Study and teaching
  - Group discussion of commonly-used verbs and phrases, 2000-04-03; 16-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:29:40; Floring, Marie; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Loudbear, Angela; Skubitz, Sarah; Zhuckkahosee, Tillie
  - Group discussion of commonly-used verbs and phrases, 2000-04-03; 16-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:12:24; Floring, Marie; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Loudbear, Angela; Skubitz, Sarah; Zhuckkahosee, Tillie
  - Group discussion of commonly-used verbs and phrases, 2000-04-03; 16-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:14:55; Floring, Marie; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Loudbear, Angela; Skubitz, Sarah; Zhuckkahosee, Tillie
  - Group discussion of commonly-used verbs and phrases, 2000-04-03; 17-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:34:53; Floring, Marie; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Skubitz, Sarah; Zhuckkahosee, Tillie
  - Group discussion of commonly-used verbs and phrases, 2000-04-03; 17-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:33:52; Floring, Marie; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Skubitz, Sarah; Snow, Margaret; Zhuckkahosee, Tillie
    A multi-part, day-long group workshop session to write down commonly-used Menominee verbs, phrases, and other vocabulary for the purposes of creating teaching material. From 15:08 to 20:00 there is a discussion of local politics and the role of teaching Menominee language and culture. Some of the participants are not identifiable.
    Keshena (Wis.); Menominee Indians--Education; Menominee language--Study and teaching; Wisconsin--Politics and government
  - Group discussion of commonly-used verbs and phrases, 2000-04-03; 18-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:28:11; Floring, Marie; Kavanaugh, Rebecca P.; Skubitz, Sarah; Snow, Margaret; Zhuckkahosee, Tillie